Oleksii Buriatov

DevOps Engineer

LinkedIn: Oleksii Buriatov | GitHub: oburiatov | oleksii.buriatov@gmail.com | Telegram: oburiatov

WORK EXPERIENCE

Kyiv, Ukraine

Big Data DevOps Engineer

Jan 2022 - present

- Migrating from on-premise infrastructure to AWS:
 - Using IaC (Terraform) for describing infrastructure
 - Configuration peerings between subnets and VPN gateways
 - Monitoring cloud infrastructure with Managed Prometheus + Grafana + ELK stack + Cloudwatch
 - Deploying services using Helm charts and Kubernetes manifests into EKS
- Migrating from on-premise infrastructure to Microsoft Azure (Jan 2022 2023):
 - Building network connectivity between on-premise and Azure (gateways, vnets, snets, peerings)
 - Set up AKS cluster, VMs, load balancers, PaaS databases etc.
 - Building docker images and deploying into AKS using GitLab CI/CD
 - Acquaintance with Azure DevOps
- Configuration system settings using Ansible
- Building CI/CD pipelines in GitLab and deploying into on-premise Kubernetes
- Administrating on-premise Big Data tools (such as NiFi, Hadoop, Spark, Airflow clusters)
- Database administration (PostgreSQL, Hive, Greenplum, MySQL)
- Deploying API using VirtualServer in Kubernetes + Keycloak authorization
- Implemented Kafka cluster with peak capacity > 1,2 M messages per seconds

Kyivstar Kyiv, Ukraine

DevOps Engineer (Internship)

Aug 2021 - Jan 2022

- Managing on-premise infrastructure (linux installation, replacing disks, disk partitioning)
- Writing Bash/Python scripts for infrastructure configuration
- Set up monitoring with Prometheus + Grafana + ELK
- Building custom images and deploying containers into Docker
- Set up deployments in Kubernetes
- Revision on-premise security infrastructure (such as connectivity and opened ports between different private networks)

EDUCATION

National Technical University of Ukraine "Igor Sikorsky Kyiv Polytechnic Institute"

Bachelor's Degree

Sep 2019 - Jun 2023

121 FICT - Faculty of Informatics and Software Engineering (Department of Computer Science and Software Engineering)

SKILLS

Hard skills	AWS, MS Azure, Linux administration, Bash/Python scripting, automation with ansible (AWX), Terraform, Gitlab, CI/CD, Docker/Kubernetes usage, set up monitoring system (Prometheus, Grafana, ELK), Jira/Confluence
Soft skills	Selflearning, diligence, team working, proactive
Languages	Ukrainian - Native, English - Intermediate

ABOUT ME

I am a DevOps Engineer, working in Big Data. I have administrative experience of Big Data instruments, such as Hortonwork DataFlow, Hortonwork Data Platform. I'm experienced in building GitLab CI/CD pipelines, building and configuring docker containers, managing Kubernetes. Also implemented monitoring system using Prometheus, Grafana and ELK stack. The basis of knowledge is Linux administrative skills.

Since January 2022, I have been taking part in data migration from the data center to the cloud (Microsoft Azure and AWS).

I'll be glad to get acquainted with you.